Abhigith Neil Abraham

Puthenkandathil house, Manakkappady, Karumalloor P.O, Aluva, Ernakulam, Kerala, India, 683511

📕+91.7907752461 | 💌 abhijithneilabrahampk@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/abhijithneilabraham | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/abhijith-neil-abraham-765165141/

Personal Profile

Entrepreneur and CTO leading products in the AI domain. 4+ years of proven experience in technology. Started career with owning open source projects, wrote research publications, performed end to end full stack applications in AI across multiple domain.

Education

College of Engineering, Trivandrum

Trivandrum, India

BTech in Electrical and Electronics

August 2016 - June 2020

Graduated with 8.1 CGPA on a scale of 10

Work Experience _____

Gomi.ai The Netherlands

Co-Founder and CTO Oct 2023 - Present

- Built an MVP end-to-end for sales demo automation in Al
- · Used technologies involving Generative AI, vector search, React for frontend and FastAPI for the backend.

Aecmaster Remote

Full Stack and AI Research Engineer

March 2023 - Oct 2023

- Led a 5-month project to integrate ChatGPT into the AEC ecosystem to understand AEC data more efficiently for customers.
- Built full stack solution make a version control alternative for AEC data that also included 3D renderings using Three is for building construction
- Developed a Chrome extension for optimized data handling in ChatGPT and a real-time platform for AEC data visualization.

Autonomio Helsinki, Finland

Machine Learning Engineer

July 2022 - March 2023

- · Authored and Open Sourced Jako, a distributed computing tool for hyperparameter optimisation using multiple machines. Responsible for building, testing and writing documentation.
- · Authored and Open sourced EasyEnergy, a tool to track carbon emissions and energy draw for Machine Learning Experiments. Responsible for the idea, roadmap, building, testing and documentation.

Saama Chennai, India

Machine Learning Research Engineer

Dec 2020 - June 2022

- · Worked with the Research team for innovating impact of machine learning with natural language processing in Clinical Domain.
- Wrote Research papers for NLP tasks such as Bio Sentence Transformers
- · Worked with internal software research team to build tools to automate cross matching of medical domain databases.

Minicog Kochi, India

Freelance Machine Learning Engineer

May 2020 - Dec 2020

- Built an open source tool named TableQA for querying natural language on tabular data.
- Wrote a research paper on TableQA.

Research Publications

- Research paper BioSimCSE: BioMedical Sentence Embeddings using Contrastive learning
- Research paper TableQuery: Querying tabular data with natural language
- Research Journal Deep Learning Applications with Python

Skills

Technical Skills

Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-learn), SQL, Postgres, Docker, Git, Vue.js, AWS, GCP, Ubuntu Linux, Real-time Data Analytics, Three.js, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, LTFX, Tableau, Firebase, Hasura, Metabase

Soft Skills

Community Management, People Relationship, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Leadership, Communication, Logical Thinking, Project Management, Team Coordination, Strategic Planning

JANUARY 31, 2024